And now, the third of our sizzles is open claw.
Open claw is massively hyped at the moment and blowing up.
And I personally rather suspect that it's going to die down a bit.
I could be completely wrong. I might be like someone that's saying,
"This chat GPT thing, it's not going to last."
But yeah, I might as well just throw it into the mix of some sizzle.
It's not, of course, related to coding agents.
It's a big hyped thing, but just to give you a sense of what it is.
So you've got the context.
It is still sort of its first of all, it was itself vibe coded.
And it's very much on the same theme of appreciating the power of these coding agents
like Cloud Code and imagining rather like co-work what happens if we apply this to
every day beyond development?
An open-glower is taking it even further.
It's described as your personal AI.
It's about really trying to be your sidekick, something that could be
there for you.
And it's also considered something that's a bit on the dangerous side,
because you run it on your computer.
You typically give it access to everything.
You connect it to everything.
That's why it has its power,
but with great power comes responsibility and comes risk. And that's why some security
professionals are very concerned about Open Claw. And one way that you could run it, of course,
in a sandbox as we discovered a couple of days ago. Anyway, Open Claw isn't completely
relevant for coding, except for seeing the potential of this stuff, so I will just quickly give you a perspective on it
so that we get our sizzle
and then we will move swiftly on.
So here is OpenClaw.
And you go to openclaw.ai to see this page.
OpenClaw, of course, was originally called
Claude Bot, spelt C-L-A-W-D, Claude Bot.
And apparently they had a letter from Anthropic,
and so they changed their name to "Maltbot",
which was still a sort of riff of this,
the lobster idea, but that they decided didn't sound,
it was hard to say, and so they changed it third time
to "Openclaw", which is what it's called now,
unless it's changed to something again, but I doubt it.
So, "Openclaw" is what we've got,
and you can install it with our one liner
That's the one line from Mac OS if you're on a Windows PC
Then this will be your one liner if you're in a power shell or this in a CMD
But you're probably in a power shell
But I'm going to go back to being on a Mac and I will run this now in a terminal
And one of the things I say is that if you don't know how to use a terminal then perhaps you're not ready to use open claw 'cause it's designed for people that know enough
about what's going on to feel like you know the risks
you're signing up for.
And of course, the main thing, as it says here,
that it runs on your computer,
that the way that you interact with it is through a chat app.
It's like got a, this native chat first experience.
You can be in WhatsApp or in Telegram,
talking to your sidekick to your cloudbot
It's got it's got memory remembers what's going on it can drive a browser
It can use anything on your computer and it's got a whole
raft of plugins that you could click into it and there in lies many of its powers
So here like I brought up a terminal. This is just a normal Mac terminal
I'm going to paste in that command to install it on my Mac. Let's give this a try. It's doing
doing a bunch of stuff and
Opened-core installer. I'm the reason your shell history looks like a hacker movie montage
Okay, and I will let it do its thing. I will see you in a sec and so I love this it says
Opened-core installed successfully the lobster. "Your terminal will never be the same."
Let's make this nice and big for you.
And then we get this Open Claw security.
Please read.
It's a hobby project still in beta.
Expect sharp edges.
It can read files, run actions,
a bad prompt can trick it to doing unsafe things.
Run an Open Claw security audit regularly. You must read the security stuff.
I understand this is powerful and inherently risky. Continue defaulting to know.
We'll go to yes, onboarding mode, quick start. And we will do the quick start.
Okay. And now we get to the models and we start with choosing a model auth provider and it's got a bunch of them.
And I think we've got enough of using anthropic.
Let's switch to open AI for a bit and use OAuth.
So I'm going to select this.
We can choose whether we want to do a chat GPT OAuth or whether we want to use an API key.
This is like an in-browser login and that is the one that we will try.
So I will do this
Continue with Google,
sign into codex with chat GPT, continue.
That's successful, return to your terminal to continue.
And now it's saying default model, keep current,
but we'll use GPT 5.3 codex.
That sounds good to me.
Select our channel, quick start.
So I'd say let's go with the telegram.
Let's do telegram.
Telegram bot token, open telegram.
And now it's telling me to do this,
and I have telegram.
So I'm going to open telegram.
I'm going to chat.
I'm going to select that I want to chat with @botfather.
I'm going to run slash new bot.
It's going to make a token, and I'm going to copy it in here. And then I'm going to run /new bot. It's going to make a token and I'm going to copy it in here and then I'm going to keep going and I'm going to do that offline so that I keep that secret and I'll see you back here in a sec.
Okay, so I did that. I set up my telegram bot following the skills now. My preferred node manager is NPM.
And I can now install skills,
different things to do stuff that might be useful for me.
And you can see all the different things it can do
by scrolling through here and get a good sense.
It could turn on and off my light bulbs.
It could do all these different things.
And let me see what we want to have it be able to do today.
Okay, so I've only chosen one simple skill, the open AI whisper, which seems like a nice
easy one. It's got no API key. It just means that there'll be access to a speech to text.
So we'll let that install and then we'll see what else we can set up.
Okay, so I went through a setup process. I had to answer a few questions. It wanted to know
what it would be called and I called it Sidekick, it kind of warring. It wanted to know what it would be called. And I called it Sidekick, it kind of warring.
It wanted to know a vibe and it wanted an emoji.
I'm definitely not cool enough to be using this product.
So I tried my best and then hooked it up to a few things.
And now it's connected to Telegram.
So I can chat with it over Telegram
and I could be doing this on my phone.
I could be doing this as I am on my computer
and my Telegram app, but this is gonna allow me now
to have a conversation with my sidekick
running on my computer.
Okay, let's give this a try.
I'm pressing start, let's have a conversation.
I'm here Edward, sidekick's ready.
Okay, please look up Tesla stock price.
stock price. If it went up today, please play me something upbeat. Otherwise something depressing. Okay, let's give it that instruction. I'm
wanting it to go and do a web search. I want it to understand what I mean figure this out and then play me music
How's it gonna do that through telegram or something?
Okay
We have music we have something playing
It went up today and so it's playing upside down by Diana Ross
And how's it playing it it's playing it because it's controlling Spotify on my computer. It's activated Spotify and it's playing Diana Ross
And here you can see the telegram
Chat I was having alongside open claw that was running on my computer in this terminal UI
Looking a lot like clawed code in a way, and it's got a message. It's replying to it
It's decided it's looked up the stock price, it went up
today, upbeat is the decision, it made a choice about what track to play, I left that up to
its autonomy, it's discretion, it put on Diana Ross, it controlled Spotify and that's
what you heard playing.
So you know that, that gives you a sense of what this is all about, people are excited
because you can drive things from just from your chat interface, it comes to you.
It can wake up and alert you about things.
It can be integrated across all of the capabilities
on your computer.
It can drive windows.
It can look things up on the web.
So it can be incredibly autonomous,
and it really brings the power of Cloud Code
and the CLI tools again that we're used to as engineers,
and it brings them to people
personally as their personal sidekick.
Okay, so that brings today to a wrap today.
Really was a light day.
We did cover the big project concerns of just the right way to approach a big repo.
And we will touch on that again tomorrow when things go really crazy.
And then after doing that, we just had some light relief
with a few things for you to look at,
like the good old Claude Agent SDK,
which is an important way to drive Claude Co-programmatically.
And then we looked at co-work,
taking what these exciting tooling
and bringing it to the professional world.
And then OpenClaw, which is bringing the same kind
of capability to a personal
world to have everyone have their own personal sidekick that you can control from telegram
from WhatsApp and have it be able to control your computer, your lights, your music, whatever
you want. And that, that is open claw. I know I just gave you a teaser of it because that's
not really what we're covering on this course, but I did want you to see it and have a feel for it.
All right, tomorrow is a massive day. Tomorrow is when we go into swarms. We look at teams.
We're going to look at a few really interesting way to orchestrate multiple agents collaborating
together in unison to achieve a bigger task. And that will lead us all the way to the capstone. And with that, amazingly, 87% is where we're at. Massive congrats.
Get ready for two big days ahead. See you tomorrow.